<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="collectionlevel" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-NNU-TL" url="http://dlib.nyu.edu/findingaids/html/tamwag/CALL_NUMBER/">tam_646</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Laura Chenven Collection of Julian and Gertrude Ascher Papers <num>TAM.646</num></titleproper><author>Rachel Schimke</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</publisher><p><date>5/7/2014</date></p><address><addressline>Elmer Holmes Bobst Library</addressline><addressline>70 Washington Square South</addressline><addressline>2nd Floor</addressline><addressline>New York, NY 10012</addressline><addressline>special.collections@nyu.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://library.nyu.edu/about/collections/special-collections-and-archives/special-collections/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://library.nyu.edu/about/collections/special-collections-and-archives/special-collections/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2020-11-30 14:33:16 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Laura Chenven Collection of Julian and Gertrude Ascher Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="local">Ascher, Julian</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="local">Ascher, Gertrude</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="dacs" source="local">Chenven, Laura</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>TAM.646</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">in 8 record cartons</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate>circa 1930-1960</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_413b9f7ac2fc045a694229e10b1826cb">Julian and Gertrude Ascher were involved in the Teachers' Union (TU) of New York City. The collection documents their work in the field of education and their involvement with the union.</abstract>
    <physloc id="aspace_9dea6465f7f074b55db2562b79d5781d">Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu at least two business days prior to research visit.</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_fa68644744002b95c1bab97931faf954">Materials are in English</langmaterial>
    <container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_ce05e7f1709e0737ddf4f80c4109c0b7" label="Mixed Materials [31142063125804]" type="box">7</container>
    <container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_1b6c8d161a3773a56f82223e0e173b2f" label="Mixed Materials [31142063125812]" type="box">8</container>
    <container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_3a24cd782711e767b62efe23e1c7a51c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">1</container>
    <container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_b6285d94c4cfa3cbb00499bf751e8334" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container>
    <container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_1b7fc9a30062caa749571093e8a6ca4d" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container>
    <container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_1202743d75af8dd5a910903a2ded1515" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">4</container>
    <container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_75f9aa3f7ebbf1d610aa59a6fc655c94" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">5</container>
    <container altrender="Record carton" id="aspace_5dd4769cc813fb8dd8ccae35a967ebb3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">6</container>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_b600a209f1735eb919f7865ecbdcee41">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Materials are open without restrictions.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_e59d5152364a657a0c825c942ede9183">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Materials donated by Laura Chenven in 2014. The accession number associated with this collection is 2014.018.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <appraisal id="aspace_4c9f2b518a1ef6bf1393bcef4b47e000">
    <head>Appraisal</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, the Tamiment Library's director, Timothy Naftali, decided to retain clippings and pamphlets related to American Communism, world Communism, and the politics of U.S. education. All original records and notes created by Julian and Gertrude Ascher were retained, but monographs were returned to Laura Chenven. In total, approximately six linear feet of monographs, pamphlets, and news clippings with inactive mold, many of which were already duplicated in the Tamiment Library's holdings, were not retained as part of the collection.</p>  </appraisal>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d738080423f4dfc519cc1c0db907ca62">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The order in which these materials were sent to the Tamiment Library has been maintained.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_194cc854e2ef22af85cf60f852de7829">
    <head>Historical/Biographical Note</head>
<p>Julian and Gertrude Ascher were involved in the Teachers' Union (TU) of New York City. The TU was organized in 1916 and chartered as Local 5 of the American Federation of Teachers (AFT). Many of the leading activists in the TU were members of the Communist Party, though the group also contained more moderate socialists and liberals. Eventually, the conflict between these two ideologically different groups would cause the majority of the TU's membership to withdraw in 1935 and found the Teachers' Guild. The TU disbanded entirely in 1964.</p>  </bioghist>
  <custodhist id="aspace_425077c21f6df17d81f8d41e57c3c8ab">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>The materials in this collection were generated and collected by Julian and Gertrude Ascher. The materials eventually passed to Laura Chenven's possession, and Ms. Chenven donated the collection to the Tamiment Library in 2014.</p>  </custodhist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_22d1fbb1ffd3bbdac10a1b9167a0c140">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Published citations should take the following form:<lb/></p><p>Identification of item, date; Laura Chenven Collection of Julian and Gertrude Ascher Papers; TAM 646; Box number; Folder number; Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, New York University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_1ba41ec597c5dc3c17f2943e51e9985b">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>The materials that were retained after preservation assessment were rehoused in archival quality boxes. Two boxes of materials were originally housed in moldy folders, but the materials themselves were not moldy. The moldy folders were replaced with new archival quality folders, and the original folder titles were transcribed onto the new folders. These boxes now comprise Boxes 7 and 8 of the collection. A collection-level finding aid was created to describe the collection, but no physical processing or arrangement was done at this time.</p>  </processinfo>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_741fd9b0b28a70d75b5e7106fdf44313">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The collection documents Julian and Gertrude Ascher's work in the field of education and their involvement with the New York City Teachers' Union (TU). The collection includes news clippings, newsletters, reports, pamphlets, and curriculum materials. Many materials on U.S. and international current events and history were likely collected as research for lesson planning or other educational purposes.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <phystech id="aspace_15b3233d7d63933c8f795b0e7068e979">
    <head>Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements</head>
<p>At the time of accessioning, extensive inactive mold was discovered. Boxes 1-6 have not been treated for mold and remain in quarantine.</p>  </phystech>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b7813020c62eb38e32bae25205e5c3b8">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive has no information about copyright ownership for this collection and is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from it. Materials in this collection, which were created in circa 1930-1960, are expected to enter the public domain in 2080.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Education -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject>
    <persname role="dnr" rules="dacs" source="local">Chenven, Laura</persname>
    <persname source="local">Ascher, Julian</persname>
    <corpname source="naf">Teachers' Union of the City of New York</corpname>
    <persname source="local">Ascher, Gertrude</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
